(AIRPLANE APPROACHES)
(TIRES SCREECH)
(P.A. JINGLES)
MAN: (ON P.A.)
United Airlines announcing
the arrival of
Flight 9435 from Beijing.
Customer service
representative,
please report to Gate C42.
(REPEATING ANNOUNCEMENT
IN MANDARIN)
(ALL CHATTERING)
WOMAN: (ON P.A.)
All visitors to the US
should line up at
booths one through 15.
CUSTOMS OFFICIAL:
Please have your I-94 forms
filled out.
What's the purpose
of your visit?
What is the purpose
Business or pleasure?
of your visit?
Just visiting. Shopping?
Euh, plaisir.
It's pleasure.
Uh, business.
How long will
you be staying
in the United States?
Could I see
your return ticket,
please?
What's the purpose
of your visit?
Business or pleasure?
Pleasure.
Enjoy your stay. Next.
WOMAN: (ON P.A.)
Please have your passports,
immigration form, I-94...
Stand by.
He's fishing.
MAN: Copy that.
See this bunch of
Mickey Mouse sweatshirts
down here?
That's the tour from China,
connecting to Orlando.
When was the last time
you saw a group
of Chinese tourists
on their way to Disney World
and not a single one of them
had a camera?
Possible forged documents
on 10 and 11.
(SHOUTING)
Sir. Sir.
Passport.
Thank you.
Welcome, Mr. Navorski.
Purpose of your visit?
(SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
Business or pleasure?
(BEEPS)
OFFICER:
Have your declarations
forms ready, please.
Sir, I have
an IBIS hit on six.
Mr. Navorski,
please follow me.
WOMAN: (ON P.A.)
...from Montreal
must proceed
to U.S. Immigration
for claiming their luggage.
All right, Mr. Navorski,
we would like for you
to wait right here, please.
Next, please.
(ELECTRIC RAZOR BUZZING)
THURMAN:
What exactly are you doing
in the United States,
Mr. Navorski?
Yellow taxicab,
please.
Take me to Ramada Inn,
161 Lexington.
Staying at
the Ramada Inn?
Keep the change.
Do you know anyone
in New York?
Yes.
Who?
No, do you know
anyone in New York?
Yes. Yes.
Who?
Yes.
161 Lexington.
Okay, Mr. Navorski,
I'm gonna need to see
your return ticket, please.
No, your return ticket.
Your...
Oh. Yes.
Ah.
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
Now, this is just
a standard procedure.
Uh, I'm going to need
the passport also.
Oh. Oh, okay.
No, no, no.
Thank you.
No, Mr. Navorski.
That.
Passport.
Mr. Navorski?
Sorry to keep you waiting.
How are you?
I'm Frank Dixon,
I'm the Director of Customs
and Border Protection
here at JFK.
Which means that
I help people with their
immigration problems.
Now, uh, we're looking
for an interpreter for you.
(STAMMERS)
How are we doing on that?
Do we have an interpreter?
Okay. Uh...
But I understand that
you speak a little English.
Yes.
Oh, you do? Okay.
Good. I hope you don't mind
if I eat while we talk.
I've a bit of bad news.
It seems that
your country has suspended
all traveling privileges
on passports that
have been issued
by your government.
And our State Department
has revoked the visa
that was going to allow you
to enter the United States.
That's it in a nutshell,
basically, right?
Anyway, it seems that
while you were in the air,
there was a military coup
in your country.
Now, most of the dead
were members of
the Presidential Guard.
They were attacked
in the middle of the night.
There was
a terrible firefight.
Uh, they got it all
on GHN, I think.
Anyway, there were very
few civilian casualties.
I'm sure your family's fine.
Mr. Navorski,
your country was annexed
from the inside.
The Republic of Krakozhia
is under new leadership.
Krakozhia! Krakozhia.
Krakozhia. Hmm.
Right.
I don't think, uh...
I don't think he gets it.
Okay...
Uh, let me...
Let me...
Okay, look.
Imagine that
these potato chips
are Krakozhia, okay?
Krakozhia.
Yes.
Okay.
So the potato chips
are Krakozhia, okay?
Okay.
And this apple...
Big Apple.
...Big Apple represents
the Liberty Rebels.
Okay?
No more Krakozhia.
New government.
Revolution.
You understand?
So all the flights
in and out of your country
have been suspended
indefinitely.
And the new government
has sealed all the borders,
which means that
your passport and visa
are no longer valid.
So, currently,
you are a citizen
of nowhere.
Now, even if we could
get you new papers,
we couldn't process 'em
until the United States
recognizes your country's
new diplomatic
reclassification.
Yeah.
See, you don't qualify
for asylum, refugee status,
temporary protective status,
humanitarian parole
or non-immigration
work travel
or diplomatic visas.
You don't qualify
for any of these things.
You are at this
time simply...
...unacceptable.
Unacceptable.
Big Apple tour includes
Brooklyn Bridge,
Empire State,
Broadway show Cats.
Well, I got more bad news
for you, Mr. Navorski.
Cats has closed.
Okay. Okay.
Now I go New York City.
Thank you.
No, Mr. Navorski, look.
I cannot allow you
to enter the United States
at this time.
Uh...
Krakozhia.
We can't allow you
to go home either.
Right.
And the thing is,
you don't really
have a home.
Yes.
You don't. Technically,
it doesn't exist.
I mean, it's like...
It's like a Twilight Zone.
Do you ever see
that show, huh?
Do you get that show
over there? Uh...
Yes, yes.
"Talking Tina,"
"Nightmare at 30,000 Feet,"
"Zanti Misfits."
"Zanti Misfits" was
Outer Limits, sir.
Oh, really?
It's not important.
Anyway...
Where do I buy
the Nike shoes?
Okay, Mr. Navorski,
come here. Walk with me.
Here's my dilemma,
Mr. Navorski.
You have no legal right
to enter the United States,
and I have no legal
right to detain you.
It seems that you have
fallen through a small
crack in the system.
I am crack.
Yes. So, until we get
this sorted out,
I have no choice
but to allow you
to enter the International
Transit Lounge, all right?
So, I am going to
sign a release form
that is going to make
you a free man.
Free?
Free.
Free. Free to go
anywhere you like
within the confines
of the International
Transit Lounge.
Okay?
Okay.
I'm sure that Uncle Sam
will have this all sorted
out by tomorrow,
and welcome
to the United States.
Almost.
(LAUGHING)
Thank you.
Okay. All right.
All right.
Thanks, Judge.
Okay.
Now, Mr. Navorski.
Mr. Navorski?
Mr. Navorski,
this is the International
Transit Lounge.
You are free to wait here.
These are food vouchers.
You can use them up
in the Food Court.
Your Krakozhian money
is no good here.
This is a 15-minute,
prepaid calling card.
You may call home,
if you like.
This, in case we need
to contact you, is a pager.
You must keep this
with you at all times.
Here is an ID badge
for you to get into CBP.
Beyond those doors...
Uh, Mr. Navorski?
Mr. Navorski,
I'm going to need
you to look at me.
Beyond those doors
is American soil.
Mr. Dixon wants
me to make it
very clear to you
that you are not
to enter through
those doors.
You are not
to leave this building.
America is closed.
America closed.
(STUTTERS)
What I do?
There's only one thing
you can do here,
Mr. Navorski.
Shop.
MAN: (ON P.A.)
Ladies and gentlemen,
passengers of flight 854...
(BRASS BAND PLAYS ON TV)
WOMAN: (ON TV)
...the international
communities
try to make inroads
to a peaceful resolution.
Meanwhile, the troubled
populace has to wonder
if they will ever find
political stability,
or find the leadership
to secure their place
on the world stage.
(SOFTLY)
Krakozhia... Oh.
And next this hour,
looking to buy
a 90-foot yacht?
Hey.
MAN: (ON TV)
...taken hostage.
We're also hearing now
that the Vice President
has been killed
along with four
cabinet members,
13 injured soldiers
and 20 civilians.
(SPEAKING BULGARIAN)
By dawn, rebel leaders
had surrounded
the state houses.
In a symbolic gesture,
the national flag
of Krakozhia was torn down
from the Presidential Palace
and the parliament building.
(VOLUME TURNS OFF)
Please. Please. Please.
Television.
(SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
FEMALE REPORTER: (ON TV)
This just in from
our overseas bureau...
Last night
a military coup overthrew
the government of Krakozhia.
Bombing and gunfire
were heard through
the night.
And although details
of the coup are unclear,
we are told that
President Vagobagin
and his top aids
have been taken hostage.
We are hearing now...
Bonjour, monsieur.
You are a Red
Carpet Club member?
(SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
I need to see
your boarding pass
and club card, sir.
I'm sorry, sir.
This is a private lounge.
The public lounge
is downstairs.
WOMAN: (ON TV)
The tiniest nation
in the region
has been shaken
by yet another uprising.
Krakozhia has been
involved in civil war
and bloody separatist
movements throughout
the late '80s and '90s
as it has tried to transition
from Communist rule.
Watch it.
Please.
Please, telephone?
Telephone?
Tele... Telephone.
Please, please.
Please.
MAN: (OVER P.A.)
For security reasons,
please keep your luggage
with you at all times.
Unattended luggage
will be removed
for inspection
and may be destroyed.
(SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God,
you broke my bag!
I got this in Paris.
This is my favorite bag.
Oh!
I can't believe you
just broke my bag.
Mom, Dad.
He broke my bag.
Food document.
Excuse me.
Stop it. Stop it.
Do you have
an appointment?
Uh...
I'm sorry, I don't let
anyone to look at my trash
without an appointment.
Uh...
I have an opening
next Tuesday.
Tuesday...
Tuesday, Monday, Tuesday,
Wednesday, Tuesday.
Tuesday.
It will be good time
for you to come back
and get lost.
Okay, goodbye.
Sorry.
Tuesday.
(STRANGERS IN THE NIGHT
INSTRUMENTAL PLAYING)
(AIRPLANE DESCENDS)
(STRAINS)
(FIZZES)
(SIGHS)
(ENGINE SCREAMS)
Don't shoot.
SALCHAK:
She sleeps 12, Frank.
DIXON: Yeah.
Has a 120-volt generator,
wet bar, gas range.
You know,
she looks amazing.
It's...
She's my dream, Frank,
my pot of gold at the end
of the rainbow.
Well,
she's a beautiful boat,
and I hope
you get her soon.
You've earned her.
Oh.
(CHUCKLES) Yeah.
Thank you, Frank.
You have.
Actually, I bought
her yesterday.
Oh, come on.
Congratulations.
Frank, I'm nominating you
to take my place.
Starting today,
you will assume the duties
of acting Field Commissioner
until you get approval
from Washington.
Really?
Uh-huh.
I don't know
what to say.
Jesus.
Richard, is this real?
Oh, it's real, Frank.
It's real.
Don't you stand there
pretending to be surprised.
Oh.
You've been waiting
for me to retire
or drop dead for years now.
No, I haven't been
waiting for you to retire.
(BOTH LAUGH)
That's all right, Frank.
My retirement
will become official
the day you get sworn in.
Uh-huh.
You've waited
a long time for this,
Frank.
I have.
Just be careful about
the inspection process.
Yeah?
I will. I've been
here for 17 years, so...
Frank, we're talking
about the Field Commissioner
position.
People are going to look
to you for leadership,
to set an example.
Well, what are you saying?
(CHUCKLES)
I'm saying the job
is yours to lose.
DIXON: Ship the Colombians
off to asylum hearings,
run priors and backgrounds
on the Chinese before
deporting.
And call the parents
of those kids from
Long Island.
Tell them it was a bad idea
to let them go to Jamaica.
Yes, sir.
Come on, everybody,
let's go.
We got South America
and Madrid on the tarmac.
I want them out of here
in half an hour, come on.
Mr. Thurman.
There's a man walking
around the terminal
in a bathrobe.
I know, sir.
You put him there.
TORRES: Next.
(SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
I need visa.
Where's your green form?
I can't do anything without
your green entry form.
Go to the wall.
Next!
Sir.
The light green form.
♪ I love New York... ♪
(SONG CONTINUES)
Light green.
Mr. Navorski...
Yes?
You cannot get
into New York
without a visa.
You cannot get a visa
without a passport,
and you cannot get
a new passport
without a country.
There's nothing
we can do for you here.
I give you light green.
I'm sorry, but you've
wasted an entire day.
At this time,
you are simply...
Unacceptable.
Yes.
VIKTOR: Unacceptable.
(SNORING)
DIXON:
Why is he still here?
You released him, sir.
You put him there.
Why the hell doesn't
he walk out the doors?
Why doesn't
he try to escape?
THURMAN:
Sir, you told him to wait.
I didn't think
he'd actually do it.
(STUTTERS)
I mean, he's in a crack.
Who the hell
waits in a crack?
THURMAN: Well,
there's no news from
the State Department,
but I think we can
deport him in a few days.
Yeah, it could be a few days.
It could be a week,
two weeks, a month.
Who knows what
this guy is thinking,
what gulag he escaped from.
Everything he does
comes back to me.
You wanna bring him
back in the holding cell?
No, I'll show
him the door.
Hello.
Do you have
an appointment?
Yes, yes.
Yes. 9:30.
Food document, trash.
Tuesday.
I hate the Tuesday.
Excuse me.
(MAN SPEAKS GERMAN)
(SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
Airports are tricky places,
Mr. Navorski.
I'm about to tell
you something.
Something that you can
never repeat to anyone.
Do you understand?
It's a secret.
Secret?
Yes, a secret.
At 12:00 today,
the guards at those
doors are going
to leave their posts
and their replacements
are going to be
five minutes late.
Late...
Late five minutes.
Yes.
At 12:00.
Just today.
Just this once.
No one is going
to be watching
those doors.
And no one is going
to be watching you.
So, America not closed.
No.
America,
for five minutes,
is open.
Have a nice life,
Mr. Navorski.
Oh.
MAN: (OVER P.A.)
United Airlines,
final boarding call...
(MUMBLES)
Catch and release, Judge.
It's very simple.
Sometimes you land
a small fish.
You unhook him
very carefully,
you place him back
in the water,
you set him free
so that somebody else
can have the pleasure
of catching him.
All right.
All right, here we go.
Okay. Call them off.
Johnson,
clear the doors.
All right.
Go, go, go...
Get out of there.
All right,
there's the door.
All right.
(INHALES)
Here we go.
Now where is he?
Oh! There he is.
No, that's not him.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
There he is.
Okay.
Oh, okay.
All right, Viktor.
Here we go.
Yep.
(WHISTLING)
(STAMMERS)
What's so complicated?
Exit, Viktor.
Come on. In a couple
of minutes, you're gonna
be somebody else's problem.
He wants to make sure
that nobody's watching.
No, I know.
I told him nobody
would be watching.
He can...
Come on.
All right,
here we go.
Come on.
This is it.
Call the Airport Police.
Call the authorities.
He's on his way.
Excuse me.
(CAMERA WHIRS)
You got it.
There we go.
Easy.
BOTH: Ah!
All right. He's got to get
a running start, I guess.
All right.
Come on, Viktor.
Just leave.
Leave. Leave.
Come on, Viktor. Come on.
What are you doing?
What's he doing?
Why is he kneeling?
Is he praying?
What, does he, like...
No, no. He's tying
his shoelace.
...pray at noon?
Isn't that...
Come on, leave.
Get the cameras.
Where is he?
THURMAN: Yeah, left.
To the left of here.
No. He was
just at the door.
I just...
THURMAN:
If you just go
a little left.
All right. All right.
(INAUDIBLE)
I wait.
What are you looking at?
What are you doing?
Go back to work.
Thank you.
(SHRIEKS)
Oh, God. Oh, shit.
(SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
Oh, man.
Oh, God.
This belong you?
Oh, thank you.
Please,
please, please.
Oh, shit.
See? (STAMMERS)
Wet floor.
That you.
I'm so late.
Buenos Aires.
I just can't
remember the gate.
Gate 24.
You sure?
Yes.
Thanks.
Wait.
Wait, wait, wait.
For you.
Payless Shoes.
Second floor.
Sensible heels.
Hi, baby.
Come here, you.
GUPTA: I think he's CIA.
The CIA put him here
to spy on us.
You don't know
what the hell
you're talking about.
That guy doesn't
even speak English.
If he could learn
to speak, this guy.
He can't speak English,
how could he have
a meeting with
a beautiful woman?
A flight attendant.
Oh, so, she's CIA, too?
No.
She look like a Russian.
KGB. She gave him heel
of her shoes.
And he gave her
a piece of the paper.
Was it microfilm?
A coupon from
Payless Shoes.
Must be some kind
of the code.
Buddy, I think you been
spending too much time
inhaling them
cleaning products.
I'm warning you guys.
You watch yourself.
This guy is here
for a reason.
And I think
that reason is us.
(MUSIC PLAYS)
Excuse me, buddy.
What's going on?
It's Navorski.
He's figured out
the quarters.
(COINS JANGLE)
Good afternoon.
Welcome to Burger King.
May I take your order?
Keep the change.
Excuse me.
(SPEAKING BULGARIAN)
Okay, okay, okay...
Okay, go. Go.
Go, go, go.
Yeah, good boy,
good boy. Good boy.
Thank you. Thank you.
Bye-bye.
Welcome to Burger King.
May I take your...
(BRASS BAND PLAYS ON TV)
"Crisis... Crisis.
Krakozhia. Krakozhia."
Now that heavy
fighting has subsided
and both sides
have dug in deep
for the long winter ahead,
it's clear that
the future of Krakozhia
may be in doubt
for some time to come.
Meanwhile,
the people of Krakozhia
suffer the consequences.
VIKTOR: (STAMMERS)
"And food..."
REPORTER: ...have caused
food and energy shortages.
"...in Krakozhia."
(SHOUTS IN BULGARIAN)
(SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
"The story of
Broadway is the..."
"The cast
"of comedy hit Friends,
"which is set in New York."
(SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
Friends.
MAN: (ON P.A.)
Ladies and gentlemen,
due to the heavy snowfall,
all flights have
been canceled...
(ALL GROAN)
(VIKTOR SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
"Wayne Newton is 61 today.
"It's a miracle.
Miracable.
"Korean conjoined twins
separated today in Miami.
"Chances of survival 50-50."
50-50.
Next.
Let me ask you something,
Mr. Navorski.
Why do you wait here
two hours every day
when I've told you
there's nothing
I can do for you?
That your new visa
will not arrive
until your country
is recognized by
the United States.
You...
You have two stamp.
One red, one green.
So?
So...
I have chance
to go New York, 50-50.
(CHUCKLES)
Yes.
That's a beautiful way
to look at it,
but America doesn't
work that way.
Mmm.
As acting
Field Commissioner,
I've created
a new position
here at JFK.
Transportation Liaison
for Passenger Assistance.
Uh, sir, what will
that person do?
(SHRIEKS)
Thank you.
I'll take it from here.
I'm Transportation Liaison
in charge
of Passenger Assistance.
No carts, no quarters.
No quarters, no food.
I'll give him a few days
before he barrels
through those doors
in clear violation
of section 214.
Then he's somebody
else's problem.
Sir, why don't we tag
him in violation
of section 2.14 now?
And then ship him
off to detention.
No, he has to break
the law by leaving
this terminal.
I won't lie, particularly
to get rid of somebody
like Viktor Navorski.
(COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING)
MAX: Sorry, buddy.
Honey!
Put it down.
You try to take my mop.
You try to take my floor.
It's my job.
Stay off my floor.
Stay away from my mop.
Food.
If you touch it again,
I kill you.
(EXCLAIMS IN BULGARIAN)
Hey. I'm Enrique Cruz.
We need to talk.
I want to make
a deal with you.
(STAMMERS)
What deal?
I need information
on CBP Officer Torres.
You feed me
information about her,
and I'll feed you.
What do you want know?
You see her every day.
Yes.
(STAMMERS) I want to know
what makes her knees weak.
What makes her blood boil
and her body tingle.
She's a wild stallion,
and you'll help me
break her.
I'm...
I'm her man of mystery.
Officer Torres
is wild stallion?
Her name is Dolores.
Yes.
You help me
to win her heart,
and you'll never
go hungry again.
I do this.
Really? Promise?
Yes. Yes.
Okay. Thank you.
What mean,
"wild stallion"?
(SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
Officer Torres.
My friend say
you are stallion.
Mr. Navorski.
Mr. Navorski, do not...
Stallion.
A what?
Stallion,
like a horse.
Stand behind
the yellow line.
It's horse.
Beautiful horse.
Behind...
What?
Who said that?
You like food?
My friend drive the food.
Mr. Navorski,
behind the yellow line.
I will help you once
you wait your turn.
I'll get light green.
Light green form, please.
I'll be back.
Okay.
(SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
She say one thing.
Very important.
What?
What did she tell you?
You don't like it?
Something wrong
with the salmon?
They need,
uh, gorchitsa.
Gorchitsa. Uh...
What?
Mustard. Mustard?
Mustard?
Yes, you have?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Please,
please, please.
Thank you.
Officer Torres,
you like the films?
Movies?
Mmm...
Not so much.
The Rockettes?
Can't afford it.
What do you like?
Conventions.
Conventions. What is?
Conventions?
This is like
secret place you go?
She go to these conventions
dressed as Yeoman Rand.
Yeoman Rand. Yes.
She's a Trekkie.
Favorite episode
is "Doomsday Machine."
(SPEAKS SPANISH)
Now, listen, Viktor.
You gotta ask her
something that
is very important.
Mmm.
Okay.
Look...
I wait.
Enjoy your visit.
Next.
Officer Torres.
Mr. Navorski.
You...
You have choose.
Man with money
or man with love?
What is choose?
So, she had a boyfriend?
Mmm.
For how long?
Two years?
What happened?
He chit.
What?
Eat shit?
He chit.
He chit. He chit.
What...
Okay, try to repeat
exactly what she said.
He chit.
She catch him. So...
He cheats.
Yes, yes.
What we call krushkach.
We say krushkach.
Uh-huh.
One man, two womans.
So. Mmm.
Crowded, you know.
Eh!
Okay. He...
He cheats.
Mmm-hmm.
You say "cheats,"
not chit.
He chit.
No, no, "cheat."
Enrique.
You, no chit.
No cheat.
No chit.
Yeah, yeah. No, I won't.
I won't. I won't cheat.
Not chit.
She's a nice girl.
She won't take
your chitting.
Next.
Officer Torres.
Have you been ever
in the love?
Enough, Viktor.
Who is it?
Who's telling you
to ask me these things?
It's a man of misery.
Misery?
Mystery?
No, no. Misery.
Man of misery.
Oh, he's so sick.
He's so in love.
But what did she say?
She did say,
"next, next."
And now she say,
"Please. Please come."
(PAGER BEEPS)
That's... Wait.
(SHRIEKS)
What, what, what...
(EXCLAIMS)
I coming.
I coming now.
No, wait. Viktor.
Viktor, just tell
me more. Hey...
I coming. I coming.
Please, please, please.
(DOOR BEEPS AND CLUNKS)
VIKTOR: Beeper went off.
Started beeping.
DIXON: Yes, we beeped you.
So, I grab. I come.
Yeah, good.
We have an idea.
Yes.
We... Okay, uh...
Would you like
something to eat?
You look like
you're starving.
Oh. No. No food.
I stuffed.
Okay. All right.
Thanks...
Thank you.
So, Mr. Navorski,
I have some very,
very good news for you.
What?
I think that I've figured
out a way to get you out
of this airport.
How?
Well, we have laws here
that protect aliens
who have a credible fear
of returning to
their own country.
If we can establish
this fear with you,
then the CBP will
be forced to begin
Expedited Removal Procedures,
to bring you to
an immigration judge
and let you plead
your case for asylum.
Asylum.
Mmm-hmm.
Unfortunately,
the courts are so backed up
with asylum cases
that the soonest
you'd get before a judge
would probably be
six months from now.
Yes, and we would
have no choice
but to let you go
for those six months.
It's the law.
You'd be released.
Right.
You would be free
to wait in New York
until your court date.
But,
believe it or not,
most people
they never show up
before the judge.
So I go New York City?
Uh-huh.
You can go to New
York City tonight.
But you only get to go
if we can establish
a credible fear.
Fear?
Mmm-hmm. Fear.
Fear.
Fear. Fear.
From what?
Well,
that's the best part.
It doesn't really matter
what you're afraid of.
It's all the same
to Uncle Sam, okay?
So I'm going to ask
you one question, Viktor,
and it's a simple question.
And if you give me
the correct answer,
I can get you out of
this airport tonight.
So, I answer
one question.
Mmm-hmm.
Go to New York City.
Tonight.
Uh-huh.
Nah...
(LAUGHS) Okay.
Okay.
Okay. All right.
Do you, at this time,
have any fear
of returning
to your own country?
Uh, no.
Okay.
Let me try it again.
Your country's at war,
Viktor.
Yes, yes. War.
Okay.
There are men in
the streets with guns.
Political persecution.
Yes, yes.
It's terrible.
Yeah, it's horrible.
It's horrible.
And God only knows
what could happen,
right?
Innocent people
are torn from their beds
and thrown into jail.
Yeah. On Tuesdays.
I hate Tuesdays.
Yeah. Yes, it's...
So you're afraid.
From what?
Krakozhia.
You're afraid
of Krakozhia.
Krakozhia?
Mmm-hmm.
No. Uh, no, I am not
afraid from Krakozhia.
I'm a little
afraid of this room.
Okay.
I'm talking
about bombs.
I'm talking about
human dignity.
human rights.
Viktor, please don't
be afraid to tell me that
you're afraid of Krakozhia.
Is home.
I am not afraid
from my home.
So?
I go to New York City now?
No.
No?
Uh...
Okay.
(STUTTERING)
I'm afraid from ghosts.
No, that's okay.
Okay.
Thanks very much.
I'm afraid from Dracula.
Thanks very much. Yep.
Thanks a lot.
Thanks, Viktor.
I'm afraid from Wolfmens...
Thanks a lot.
We'll see you again.
...afraid from sharks.
Okay, thank you, Viktor.
Thanks.
Thanks a lot.
(GROANS)
(LAUGHS)
Why you do this?
Nobody read
the sign in America.
This is the only
fun I have.
AMELIA: A barbecue?
That's why I'm not
going to see you?
Let me get this straight.
I change my schedule
to meet you.
I take four
back-to-back flights,
fly 27 hours straight
literally around the world,
and now you tell me
you're going to spend
the 4th of July
with your wife?
The woman hates fireworks.
Don't lie to me, okay?
I know for a fact
you took her to Rome
last weekend.
Because you flew United, Max.
(SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
(SOBS)
You make it a habit
out of listening
to other people's
conversations?
No, I try to call home.
So then...
You know why men
are such assholes?
No.
Because they're all liars.
(STAMMERS)
Wait, wait, wait...
Wet, wet, wet...
Wet floor.
Wet, wet.
Please, please.
Don't be hurt.
How can I not be?
He's married.
One man. Two womens.
Crowded.
You want to know
what the worst part is?
I never even asked
him to leave his wife.
I was encouraging
him to get counseling.
I mean, what kind
of sick person am I?
I'm rooting
for the home team.
(SOBS)
I just wish the sex
wasn't so amazing.
(LAUGHS)
Okay.
So amazing.
All right.
Bye-bye.
You know,
sometimes in the mornings,
I just stare at him
over room service.
Watch him do
the crossword puzzle.
I start to think that maybe,
maybe this could happen.
That we belong together.
Uh...
This man has you.
Why he need puzzle?
This is my problem.
I always see men
the way I want to see 'em.
Do I know you
from someplace?
Sensible heels.
Payless Shoes.
Second floor.
(SNORTS) It's cool.
Oh.
You headed for home?
Uh...
No, no. I am...
I am delayed
a long time.
I hate it when
they delay flights.
What do you do?
Oh, I go from one building
to another building.
I have beeper.
Oh, contractors.
You guys travel
as much as we do.
Ah.
Sorry about that.
Thank you very much.
What's "BH"?
In English,
Viktor Navorski.
Amelia Warren.
Amelia Warren?
Yeah.
Nice to meet you.
You, too.
Nice to see you again.
Again.
You like Italian food?
I know, it's late
and you've probably
got other plans,
but if you'd like to grab
some dinner right now,
we can run right out
and catch a cab.
I know a place that has
the greatest cannelloni.
Uh...
(STAMMERS)
No, I can't.
You married?
No.
Girlfriend?
I can't go out with you.
God. I am so...
I'm so sorry.
I am so sorry.
I must come off
like a complete
nut job or something.
No, no.
I just...
I didn't want to eat alone.
You ever done that before?
Wet, wet...
Wet floor.
Wet, wet floor.
VIKTOR: No, I...
AMELIA: No, please.
You don't have to explain.
No, I...
It's fine.
Nadia.
In New York restaurant,
what cost is cantaloni?
I don't know.
Maybe 15 bucks.
Dollars?
Twenty.
Two people, 40.
(GASPS)
Two people,
40 dollars.
Two people, 40 dollars.
I help you?
I'm so sorry, sir.
The position has
already been filled.
Do you live nearby?
Yes, yes.
Gate 67.
Because we are very
particular about punctual...
Did you say Gate 67?
Gate 67.
(LAUGHS)
You got to be kidding.
You got to help me
help you.
I don't see a Social
Security number, your
Driver's License number...
...mailing address,
even a phone number.
Telephone?
You need?
Yeah.
I get. I get.
I get phone.
All right.
(STAMMERING)
I get phone.
451-1226.
All right.
When's the best time
to reach you?
Now?
(PHONE RINGS)
Hello?
CLIFF:
Hi, Mr. Navorski.
Yes,
this is Viktor Navorski.
Who calls?
It's Cliff, the Manager
of the Discovery Store.
Ah! Cliff. Hello.
(CHUCKLES) Yeah.
How's it going?
Good, good, good.
Is this a good time?
Oh, yes,
I wait for your call
the whole day.
Yeah, well, unfortunately,
I got to tell you that
the position's been filled.
Oh.
Yeah, so could you please
go sit someplace else?
Yeah,
I go to bathroom now.
That'd be good.
Thank you.
All right.
CLIFF: Okay.
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
(SHRIEKS)
Who is this?
Who are you?
WORKER: It's no one.
There's no one here
for another two weeks.
This isn't one of my guys.
(TURNS OFF MUSIC)
Look at this cornicing.
This is good work.
Must be Harry's crew.
You with Harry's crew?
Does Harry think
he's running this job?
I go now.
Go? Go where?
Gate 67.
67?
We're ten months
away from 67.
He's got to be Harry's.
If he's not mine,
and he's not yours...
Harry's trying
to make me look bad.
I've got to slow that prick
down before he gets to 67.
What's your name?
Viktor Navorski.
Bobbie,
pull him off Harry's crew,
put him on mine.
You start 6:30
Monday morning.
You...
You give me job?
(GASPING)
6:30, yes, boss.
(JAZZ PLAYS
ON PERSONAL STEREO)
ENRIQUE: We have
lobster ravioli
from Alitalia.
MAN: Good.
ENRIQUE: We have caviar
from Russian Aeroflot.
GUPTA: Okay, okay.
Just bring it.
ENRIQUE: Hey, Viktor.
Hello, all.
Look.
Look. The man
without a country.
Come on in.
Welcome.
I see this.
Yeah, you did well.
Have a seat.
Here?
Here.
Come on, sit down.
Hey, who invited him?
I did. We needed
a fourth, right?
I'm not going
to play with him.
Oh, Gupta, relax,
would you?
He ain't a spy.
How do you know?
He could be recording
everything we say.
A wire in his shirt.
A microphone up
in his ass.
I'm not going
to lose my job.
Fine.
Will you feel better
if we X-rayed him?
GUPTA: Yes.
Close your eyes.
Okay.
So you are clean.
Good.
Let's play cards.
I will have money.
But Friday.
Don't worry about it.
We don't play for cash.
We play for unclaimed items
from the Lost and Found.
You'll be amazed
at what people leave
at airports. Come.
I have two nines
and two nines.
Oh. Four nines.
Four nines.
Thank you.
Four nines. Wow.
Careful, careful.
Watch out.
Wait, wait.
Hey,
we have a question
for you, Viktor.
Yeah,
we're just curious.
What is in the can?
What? This?
Yeah, we saw the X-ray.
We know there's
no nuts in there.
What is in there?
This is jazz.
Jazz?
Jazz, yes.
Yes.
(ALL LAUGH)
You sure
it's jazz in there?
Check again,
it might be the blues.
Or some salsa.
Yeah,
maybe Stevie Wonder.
No, no, is jazz.
Okay, guys. Okay.
For tonight's
grand prize,
we have...
Show them, Gupta.
Oh.
I found this upstairs.
Virgin Air,
first class lounge.
There you go.
And they belong to?
Cher.
Cher?
As in Cher?
Yeah.
Cher.
I checked it out.
There were witnesses.
Those are Cher's panties.
Ready?
Hurry up.
So, will we share
the panties?
No, no, no.
Not if I win.
Come on.
Wait a second.
WOMAN: (ON P.A.)
...flight number 801 to Narita
is now announcing
final boarding...
VIKTOR: "You can't.
That is mine."
"You can get so confused."
Viktor? Well, hi.
Oh.
Ooh...
Please, please,
please.
How are you?
Please... Good, good.
Oh, man.
I've got to say
I am so sorry about
what happened last time,
you know,
asking you out like that.
I'm so used to guys
trying to grab my ass
at 30,000 feet
that when I finally
meet somebody who keeps
his hands in his pocket,
I don't know how
to react, so...
Let's just
start over, huh?
Yes, okay.
Are you coming
or going?
I don't know.
Both.
Tell me about it.
Napoleon?
Yeah. Yeah. I read
a lot of history books.
They're long and cheap
and usually about
men killing each other.
Like 1,200 pages for $9.99.
You can't beat that.
But Napoleon?
Yeah.
He's one of my favorites.
Oh.
You know what
saved Napoleon's life?
No.
His ego.
Ego?
Yep.
After he loses
the Battle of Waterloo,
Napoleon isolates himself
on the tiny island
of Saint Helena.
Now, no one knows exactly
what happens next,
but the version
I like goes like this.
He's very depressed
and he decides to take
his own life.
But Napoleon believes
himself to be of such
superhuman strength
that he takes six times
the amount of poison
needed to do the job.
I mean, his stomach
is so full up with poison
that his body rejects it,
and he doesn't die.
See? Ego.
Mmm.
Saved his life.
Maybe he need glasses.
Glasses?
Yes.
To read words on bottle.
Poison.
You know, it's funny
you should say that.
Rumor has it
that Napoleon
was farsighted.
There you go.
And there you go.
I think we're rewriting
history right here.
Why don't we talk
about it over lunch?
Oh, my God.
I can't believe it.
I just asked you out again.
I just did it again.
(LAUGHS)
I'm so... Just stay away
from me, Viktor, okay?
I'm sick.
I don't have the ability
to be alone for five seconds.
Okay.
Okay, what?
Lunch with you.
You'll have lunch
with me?
Yes.
You're not running
for a flight or...
I wait.
(PAGER BEEPS)
Oh...
It's me.
You. Yes.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I just got paged.
You work?
No.
Ah.
Three of you.
Crowded.
Stay away from me,
Viktor.
I'm...
I have a serious problem.
I'm as bad as Napoleon.
I just keep ingesting
these poisonous men
until I make myself sick.
You're not sick,
Amelia. No.
No?
No. You're farsighted.
I have to go.
I have to stay.
Story of my life.
Oh! Me, too.
THURMAN:
Your CBP inspection's
in three days.
The FBI and Homeland
Security will tour
the airport at 9:00am,
spend two hours
observing these offices
before your
interview process begins.
How much does
Navorski make?
Sir?
How much does he make?
How much are they paying him?
I believe they're
paying him cash
under the table, sir.
I know that.
How much?
$19 an hour.
Unbelievable.
Do you know
that's more than I make?
That's New York City
construction.
You know, one of my own men
came up to me the other day.
Asked me if I wanted
to join the big pool.
Look at him.
Look at him. Look at him.
Place a bet on
when Navorski's going
to leave this airport.
Have you heard about this?
I have January 3rd.
Bring him in.
Jake,
he has no nationality.
Okay? No country.
So, automatically,
he's a national
security risk,
according
to my interpretation
of Section 2.12.
So all I'm asking for,
is that you to put him
in a federal detention center
and run a clearance on him.
That's all I want.
Well,
what about a federal prison?
what about another airport?
Hello? Hello?
God damn it!
I'm just detaining so many
people, there's no goddamn
room anywhere.
Did you try the FBI?
Yes, I tried the FBI.
I tried everybody.
Nobody'll take him.
You want me
to bring him back
to the terminal?
No. From now on,
Navorski lives here.
The people who are
coming here today
will be observing me,
inspecting me.
But most of all
they will be looking
at the way that
this airport is run.
So let's show them
why this is
the number one airport
in the United States.
We process about
600 planes a day,
with a processing time
of 37 minutes per plane,
about 60 seconds
per passenger.
Uh, to be brought into
the country, foodstuff...
We keep it as
clean as possible.
Um, import, export.
What do you import?
Computer software.
That's a lot of walnuts.
Um, yeah.
Yeah, my mother-in-law
loves these things.
Every time I go on business
to Brazil, she makes me
bring her back a bag.
Your mother-in-law?
Yeah.
Mind if I try one?
How did you know
those weren't for
his mother-in-law?
Well, if he's married,
where is his wedding ring?
And if he's divorced,
who in their right mind still
talks to their mother-in-law?
(INSPECTORS CHUCKLING)
I'm sorry,
I mean, but really.
No offense
to mother-in-laws, but...
Sir.
Yeah.
Sir, we have
a situation upstairs.
Well, it's gonna
have to wait.
No. This won't wait.
When the 9:12
from Toronto landed,
they found
four prescriptions
without an MPL.
They tried to take
the pills away from him,
and he went nuts.
There he is.
We think they're
for his father.
No, no, no.
Sir, sir, calm down.
Put your weapons down.
Everybody keep
your weapons...
All right.
We're here to help you.
We're here to help you, sir.
All right. Give me the knife.
Where's he from?
He's from Russia.
The only interpreter
we got is in Newark.
He'll be here in an hour.
Okay, we gotta
find somebody
to talk to this guy.
I have an idea, sir.
Okay.
Viktor.
(SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
(GROANS)
I need your help.
His name is Milodragovich.
He lives across the border
from you.
He may not speak
exactly your dialect
or whatever,
but I need you to translate
and help me out
of a jam.
I help you? Why?
Because I don't want
anybody to get hurt, Viktor.
This guy's very upset.
Just talk to him
and calm him down, all right?
You do that,
I'll let you back
in the terminal.
No. New York.
FEMALE OFFICER:
Coming through!
No red stamp.
Green. I green.
New York.
Okay, yes.
You say yes?
Yes.
Yes?
Yes. Yes!
Okay. Okay, okay, okay.
Stay out! Stay out!
Mr. Milodragovich,
we have somebody here
to talk to you.
Stay out!
Somebody to talk to you.
Go ahead.
Stay out. Stay out.
Okay. Okay.
(SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
(SPEAKS RUSSIAN)
So?
Okay,
tell him in order to export
medicines from this country,
he needs to have
the proper form,
a Medicinal...
(SPEAKS RUSSIAN)
...a Medicinal
Purchase License.
Okay?
You understand me, Viktor?
(SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
He say he bring
the medicine for his father.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Okay.
(ALL CLAMORING)
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
This why he go to Canada.
This why. Medicine for father.
It doesn't matter.
His plane landed
in the United States.
Uh-huh.
He needs to have
the right form.
Okay. Okay.
(SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
He did not know he
need this document.
No one say to him
he need document form.
Well, I'm saying it to him.
He needs to have
the form signed by
the local hospital
who is treating his father
and a doctor in Canada.
These medicines have to
stay in the United States
now that they're here.
They have to stay here.
(SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
He's begging you.
I know.
I can see that he's begging.
I can see that.
I'm sorry, sir.
You'll have to
take a flight in
the morning.
The medicine stays here.
I'm sorry.
Uh...
(SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
WOMAN: Send him down.
(MILODRAGOVICH SOBS)
All right. All right.
Thank you, Viktor.
Good job. Let's go.
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
Oh, oh, oh, hey. Uh...
Goat.
What?
Goat. Goat.
Medicine is for goat.
Goat?
Yes. Yes.
Medicine is for goat.
(MIMICS BRAYING) Goat.
(WHIMPERS)
He said that?
Yes.
He say...
We not understand.
I not understand "goat".
Why? What are you saying?
You misunderstood him?
That the medicine
is not for his dying father?
VIKTOR: No. No.
(STAMMERING)
The... Krakozhia...
The name for "father"
sound like "goat".
I make mistake.
(CHUCKLES)
Why are you
doing this, Viktor?
Medicine is for goat.
No, it's not.
Yes.
No. No. No.
Yes. Yes. Yes.
You've been reading
the immigration forms.
The blue one.
Blue?
Yep. Blue.
Blue. The blue form.
The one that says
if it's an animal,
he doesn't need
the Medicinal Purchase
License.
You know it. No.
Then he can just
bring the drugs in.
That's very good, Viktor.
That's very good.
Why are you doing this? Huh?
You don't know him.
You don't know the rules.
Look at me.
I was going to help you.
Now I want you to ask him
one last...
Well, he's said...
No, not you.
I want you to ask him.
I want to hear him say it.
I want to hear him say
who the medicine is for.
Please.
Who the medicine is for.
(SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
Answer him, Mr. Milodragovich.
Who are the pills for?
Okay. The pills stay.
He goes. That's it.
Come on now. Let's go.
Easy.
Take it easy. Come on.
(WHISPERS) Goat.
Please. For goat.
Medicine for goat.
Give him the pills.
Medicine... Medicine...
(VIKTOR SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
OFFICER: Come on now.
He love that goat.
Do you think
this is a game? Huh?
Do you think I need an excuse
to put you back in that cell
to keep you there
for five years?
You go to war
with me,
and you go to war
with the United States
of America.
And then you'll know
when that fight is over
why the people of Krakozhia
wait in line for
cheap toilet paper
while Uncle Sam wipes his ass
with Charmin two-ply.
GUPTA: There was a 20 man.
Immigration gun was drawn.
The Dixon was ready to fire.
To kill the little
man with the pills.
But then someone
walks into the room
and stand in front
of this little man.
"Put the guns away,"
the man say.
"Nobody will die today."
MAN: Who?
Who was it that saved him?
Yeah, tell us.
Who was it?
(ALL SPEAKING)
Who was this man?
Navorski.
Viktor "The Goat" Navorski.
It doesn't look good, Frank.
I was just
following the rules.
Sometimes you have
to ignore the rules,
ignore the numbers,
and concentrate on the people.
The people. Yeah, I know.
The people, compassion, Frank.
That's the foundation
of this country.
(SIGHS) I know. I know.
Yeah.
You could learn
something from Navorski.
Cheer up. It's not over yet.
(SIGHS)
Is that for me?
Yes. Yes.
Is Virgin Isle sailfish.
For you.
For wall.
Fish for wall.
Why do you want
to go to New York, Viktor?
And what's in
the can of peanuts?
(STAMMERING)
Promise.
A promise in the can?
Yes.
Yes. A promise.
Let me make you a promise,
Viktor.
And this is
a promise that comes
from a man who is stuck here.
A man who may be stuck here
for the next 10 years.
From now on,
you and I are partners.
If I stay, you stay.
You will not set one foot
in New York City.
Not a single toe
in the United States
of America.
Do you understand
what I am saying to you?
Yes.
You don't like fish.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Do you ever feel
like you're just
living in an airport?
You know, we don't
have to do this, Viktor.
I can ship you out
in a crate.
I can literally mail you
anywhere in
the United States.
Hey, what about
my food cart?
He can hide inside,
and we'll drive right out.
No. No. No. I can't...
I can't do this.
Viktor, I thought you said
you wanted us to help you.
I do.
Okay, well,
what's her name?
Amelia Warren.
I thought we were looking
for a way out, not a way in.
Okay. Here.
You better be careful.
You know,
those flight attendants ain't
like regular women, Viktor.
They're flying back and forth
between all those time zones,
kinda messes with their
biological clock or something.
They're always ready for sex.
Why you think
they can't stop smiling?
Okay, I found something.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Shh!
GUPTA: I am leaving.
They will come for us.
Gupta, will you relax?
Just go out there
and watch the door.
You go in jail. Not me.
MULROY: Oh, for...
You know what? Forget it.
Just keep looking.
Warren you said, right?
Yes. Yes.
Warren.
Amelia Jane Warren?
Jane?
Yeah.
Ooh, way to go, Viktor.
First class.
When she come back?
Uh... Three weeks.
(WHISPERS) Oh...
Amelia, would you like to
get eat to bite?
Bite to eat? Cantaloni?
Bite to eat?
Eat to bite? Eat to bite.
Bite to eat.
Bite to eat. Bite to eat.
Bite to eat?
Gupta, you been
ever married?
What did you say?
You been ever married?
I had a wife
and two kids in India.
I left them
there 23 years ago.
Why?
I had a small
tobacco shop in Madras.
Made just enough
money to survive.
One day this
policeman comes in
and tells me I
owe him some tax.
I said okay.
This is common. So I pay him.
But the next day,
the same policeman come
and keep coming
and keep coming.
And I am paying,
and I'm paying him,
and I'm paying him.
And finally,
on the fifth day,
I take a knife and I
stab him in his chest.
You killed policeman?
No. I just missed his heart.
When they tried to arrest me,
I just run away.
So you never go home?
Oh, if I go home,
I go in the jail
for seven years.
What if
United States catch you?
They deport you.
As long as I keep
my floor clean,
keep my head down,
they have no reason
to deport me.
They have no reason
to notice a man like me.
(P.A. CHIMES)
WOMAN: (ON P.A.)
United Airlines
Flight 2703 from Rome, Italy,
is now arriving at Gate C43.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(CART BEEPS)
Hey, wait.
Sorry. I'm sorry.
No, no, no. It's wet. Wet.
Hey!
Watch where you're going.
Watch out.
(VIKTOR GRUNTS)
Ooh!
Amelia.
Viktor.
Hello.
Sorry. I'm sorry.
He nearly killed me.
You okay?
I'm fine.
I love the suit.
Oh.
Hugo Boss.
On sale, $149.99.
(GIGGLES)
That's a bargain.
Yes.
Napoleon?
Uh, yes, yes.
And Josephine.
Do you know what Napoleon
gave Josephine on
their wedding day?
Amelia?
Would you like to
have eat to bite?
Food. Tonight?
You're asking me
out for dinner?
Yes.
Yeah. Sure.
What time?
Dinnertime.
AMELIA:
Where do you want to go?
Uh, I know place.
Do you have an appointment?
Navorski.
This way, please.
Thank you.
I didn't know they
had a patio up here.
It's very nice.
(INAUDIBLE)
Good night.
Please. Please. Please.
Sorry. So, tonight we have
cannellonis or chicken.
Cannelloni, please.
Cannelloni.
Sorry.
Thank you.
For you, sir?
Uh... Same.
That's a great, great choice.
I'll be back.
Let me see. Enjoy.
Did you know the croissant
was invented in Romania?
Tell me.
Okay.
Um, it's 1742,
and the Turks
invade Bucharest,
making a surprise attack
under the cover of night.
But the town bakers...
(PAGER BEEPS)
Sorry.
(CLATTERING)
So, the bakers?
No, never mind.
It's a dumb story.
No, please.
I'm sorry, Viktor.
Nobody really cares
where the croissant
was invented.
I'll bet the Romanians
themselves don't really
give a shit.
I care.
Is histories. Is truth.
I'm 39 years old.
No.
Yeah.
That's the truth.
You are not.
Mmm-hmm.
I tell everybody I'm 33,
and most of the men I've
dated think I'm 27, but no.
I'm 39.
So? I was 39 once.
I was 18 years old
when I started
working for the airlines.
I've been doing
this over 20 years.
And now there's
no more pretending.
This is it.
It's why my
address book is
alphabetical by city,
and my pager will
always go off during dinner.
(PAGER BEEPS)
You can switch off pager.
I wish I could.
I've been waiting
for a phone call
for seven years.
I know it's coming, Viktor.
That's why I
can't break it off.
That's why I live
out of hotels
and have my little suitcase
packed, ready to go,
just in case
he wants to meet
me for the weekend.
Yeah.
I've been
waiting my whole life.
Just don't know
what the hell for.
(PAGER VIBRATES)
I'm so sorry.
I live here.
What?
I live here, in terminal.
Gate 67.
You live at the airport?
Yes. Day and night.
This home, like you.
They tell me to wait.
So I wait.
All frequent fliers
feel the same
way you do, Viktor.
Everybody's waiting.
Everybody.
No.
For a flight,
for a meeting...
No, no, no.
I don't wait for flight.
I don't wait for meeting.
Then what are
you waiting for?
(PAGER BEEPS)
Is okay. I understand.
I have an idea.
Come here.
(STAMMERING) What you do?
(GASPS)
You sure?
More than anything,
I'm sure of this, Viktor.
Ready?
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH LAUGH)
VIKTOR:
So, when do you come back?
AMELIA: 13 days.
How about you?
VIKTOR: I... I will be here.
AMELIA: But what if
your schedule changes?
Maybe we should
exchange phone numbers.
VIKTOR: No. I will be here.
You know what Napoleon
give to Josephine
when he win Bavaria?
Tell me.
Oh, come on. Tell me.
I will show you.
13 days from now.
Hmm?
(CAMERA WHIRS)
(FLUSHES)
What's he doing?
I can't ask him
what he's doing.
I'm supposed to tell him
If I ask him,
I look like an idiot.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
I'm sorry. Sorry.
Please, you got to
do this for me.
I promise you're gonna get
really fat with all the food
I'm going to give you.
But, please, do this for me.
It will be the last
thing I ask you to do.
He waits for you
to answer at Sbarro.
I have to work.
He will wait.
(CHEERING)
(VIKTOR CHUCKLES)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
How was your flight?
Good.
Thanks.
Is something wrong?
You'll have to
come with us, ma'am.
You gotta be kidding.
I come through here
twice a month.
Please follow me.
(SIGHS)
I'm supposed to be
meeting somebody.
(P.A. CHIMES)
(MAN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY ON P.A.)
DIXON: In my line of work,
there are three
things that matter.
The person,
the document and the story.
Find the truth of one,
and you find
the truth of all three.
I need your help
finding the truth.
Do you know a man
named Viktor Navorski?
Yes.
Do you know why he's here
and where he's from?
No. We're just friends.
Have you noticed
that he hides a can
of Planters dry roasted
peanuts in his bag?
So?
What do you make of that?
(CHUCKLES)
I'd make peanut butter,
I guess.
(CHUCKLES)
We know that
he's planning to go
to the Ramada Inn
on Lexington.
Has he told you
why he's in New York?
No.
Has he told you
where he lives?
No.
We just met at the airport.
All I know is that
he's a building contractor,
living out of a suitcase.
That's it.
He's a contractor?
Yeah.
That's what he said?
Mmm-hmm.
Amelia. I'm just curious.
You are the kind of woman
who can get any guy she wants.
Why Viktor Navorski?
That's something
a guy like you
could never understand.
I guess you missed
your flight again.
Or maybe you have
a bad travel agent.
Please. Please. Sit.
It's okay, Viktor.
All men lie.
At least you're
not very good at it.
I did not lie.
You told me you were delayed.
You never said it
was for nine months.
Maybe you see the man
the way you want see the man.
So, what am I seeing?
Who are you?
I...
Unacceptable?
Yes. Yes.
You want to hear
the funny part?
I broke up with him.
I was coming here to tell you
that he's out of my life.
I'm free.
I got tired of waiting.
At least we have
that in common.
Amelia, you know what Napoleon
give to Josephine
when he win Bavaria?
(WHISPERS) No.
I show you.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Please. Please.
Sit. Please.
That was gift.
Napoleon to Josephine.
One thousand fountains.
You built this for me?
Please. Sit. Sit.
Don't get wet.
(VIKTOR STRAINS)
VIKTOR: Come on.
Oh... (SPEAKS BULGARIAN)
It no work.
It should shoot,
big water up to ceiling.
Just tell me the truth.
Did you escape
from an institution?
Huh?
Are you a criminal?
You're living here, Viktor.
You're living at Gate 67.
I just want to know why.
Here. I show you.
My father.
Oh, God, Viktor,
please tell me
your father isn't
in that peanut can.
This is jazz.
My father,
Dimitar Asenov Navorski,
see this photograph
in Hungarian newspaper, 1958.
He say he look at photograph
for seven days.
Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday...
Who are they?
Oh.
Count Basie, Dizzy Gillespie,
Thelonious Monk,
Sonny Rollins,
Art Blakey, Max Kaminsky.
57 of them all together.
After looking at photograph
for seven days,
my father has idea.
He begin to write
letters to club,
New York, Lickety Split,
Snookie's Sugar Bowl.
He ask the nuns
to write English.
Hundreds letters.
And then he wait.
He wait month, week, year.
My father wait 40 year.
And they all sign names.
One by one.
They all write their name
and send it to my father.
All but not one.
Benny Golson.
Saxophone.
My father die
before Benny Golson
write his name
and send to my father.
So I make him promise.
I keep promise.
I promise I will go New York,
find Benny Golson,
have him write
name to put in can.
And you've been living here
all this time so you could
do this for your father?
Maybe I think
he do it for me.
You say you are
waiting for something.
And I say to you, "Yes, yes.
We all wait."
What are you waiting for?
You. I wait for you.
What?
The war is over.
...the right
wing military coup
that ousted
President Vagobagin...
(ALL SING THE KRAKOZHIAN
NATIONAL ANTHEM IN BULGARIAN)
All right, everybody.
Come on.
Let's raise your glasses.
Let's have
a toast to my friend,
Viktor "The Goat."
(BLEATS)
(ALL BLEAT)
May he never lose
his country again.
(GUFFAWS)
Krakozhia.
Amelia. Amelia.
You... You...
You here early.
Hello. Amelia. Oh, look.
Peace.
Peace. The war. The war.
Please come. Come.
See, the war,
the war Krakozhia is over.
Peace. The war is over.
You know my friend?
Yes.
He works...
He works in Washington.
Yes, yes.
He has a lot of connections.
Here.
Oh.
It's a pass, Viktor.
A one-day
travel emergency visa
with your name on it.
Wha... Visa?
Yes.
From your friend?
Yeah.
Just go to New York,
find that last name
and put it in the can.
I go New York?
Yes.
I go New York!
(ALL CHEER)
Amelia, you come with.
You come with me to New York.
Your friend do this for me?
Why he do this for me?
He did it for me.
I told you to stay
away from me, Viktor.
But you didn't understand.
I think you were confused.
No. No, no, no.
No, I confused
about everything.
I not confused...
Not this. Not this.
I'm sorry.
I'm running late.
Amelia.
Why you go? Why you go?
You know what Napoleon
gave Josephine as
a wedding present?
It was a gold locket.
And on the inside,
he made an inscription.
"Destiny."
Destiny.
WOMAN: (ON TV)
...rejoice in the streets
as well as in
their local taverns.
In the distance,
the Krakozhian flag
waved goodbye
from high atop
the parliament buildings.
It is a clear
sign of the power...
Hey, baby.
Hi.
I missed you.
Come on.
TORRES: Next.
Viktor.
Hello, Dolores.
How I am today?
What do you have here?
Oh, no. It's not signed.
What?
This is a one-day
emergency travel visa.
To validate authenticity,
it needs to be signed
by the supervising officer.
Dixon?
Yes.
Dixon.
The war in
my country is over.
Yeah. I know.
Congratulations.
It's strange,
isn't it, Viktor?
When you wait so
long for one thing?
One tiny moment.
I had that moment today, too.
You see this badge?
This badge means
that I was made
CBP Field Commissioner.
It means that
my authority
over the security of this
airport is absolute.
Your ticket
and your passport.
It's time for you
to go home.
Officer Waylin, will you
please show Mr. Navorski
into the terminal
and make sure that
he does not miss his flight.
Goodbye, Viktor,
and good luck.
I think I want
go New York City.
(SIGHS)
Don't make this difficult,
Viktor.
I no more "unacceptable."
I told you this is over.
I go New York.
Are you sure you
want to do that?
I go New York City now.
Part of my job
as Field Commissioner
is to get rid of undesirables,
and there are quite a few.
Like this guy, Joe Mulroy.
I think you know him.
Joe's been here
for about 20 years,
but it turns out
he's been running
an after-hour poker game.
Bringing in
liquor and marijuana.
Poor guy's going
to lose his pension.
And I think he has kids, too.
Yep.
And then there's
this guy, Enrique Cruz.
I think you
also know Enrique.
Enrique, as it turns out,
has been letting people
into the food
preparation area.
That's a major
security breach.
The poor guy,
I think he's a newlywed.
But I'm going to
have to let him go.
And then there's Gupta Rajan.
He's a janitor.
But as it turns out,
he's wanted for assaulting
a police officer
back in India in 1979.
I'll have to deport him.
I will go home.
I'm sorry.
What did you say?
I will go home.
Leave them alone.
I will go.
Today.
Yes.
If you don't
get on that plane, Viktor,
they're all gone.
Yes, yes.
Do you understand?
Yes. Yes.
Okay. Good.
(P.A. CHIMES)
(WOMAN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY ON P.A.)
I don't believe you.
Viktor,
you don't have to do this.
Viktor, you can
fight these guys, okay?
We'll help you.
Viktor, come on.
I owe you so much.
Please let me help you.
Viktor, listen to him.
This is your friend talking.
Viktor,
we're all your friends.
We're your family now.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Gupta.
Goodbye.
You try to fool us.
You make us to think you would
walk out those door,
that you will
fight with them.
Why don't you fight?
The war is over.
Then go. Get lost.
Get lost.
Go home and tell them
you never make it.
You come this
close to America,
but you don't have the courage
to go from here to here.
You are a coward.
(P.A. CHIMES)
The plane is on time.
You are a coward.
You are a coward!
You make me sick!
Gupta!
What's wrong with you, man?
Settle down.
Got people looking all around,
looking at me like I'm...
(SIGHS)
Look at me.
Come on, look at me.
(SIGHS)
There's something
you should know.
(WHISTLES)
WOMAN: (ON P.A.)
Ladies and gentlemen,
United Airlines Flight 865
from Krakozhia has landed
and is now taxiing
to the gate.
For those passengers
holding tickets for
Flight 866 to Krakozhia,
we expect departure
to be on schedule.
Gupta.
Gupta!
(SIREN BLARING)
I am going home.
Get lost.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
WOMAN: (ON P.A.)
Your attention, please.
Flight 866 to Krakozhia
will be delayed
until further notice.
(GUNS COCK)
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
Do you have an appointment?
Would somebody please tell me
what the hell is
going on down there?
We're right behind you.
Viktor's leaving.
Monica, Viktor's leaving.
I know. He's going home.
He's going for the front door.
He's going out to the city.
What? Oh, my...
(ALL CLAMORING)
Viktor. Remember us.
I'm full.
Hey, on behalf
of Discovery Store,
I want to give you this
little blue squishy.
You squish it.
It's good luck.
A digital camera
for Cousin Katia.
I don't know
where you're going, Viktor,
but these will
keep your feet warm
when you get there.
Okay, everybody in position?
THURMAN: We're here.
That's it.
Secure the door.
(ALL TALK AT ONCE)
WAYLIN: Sorry, Viktor.
Take him, Judge.
Hold it, Viktor. Take it easy.
You see those doors?
Those are the entry doors
to New York City.
To the United
States of America.
Turn around.
It's snowing in the city,
and you're going to need that.
(PEOPLE CHUCKLING)
Good luck.
Oh, no. Oh, no.
No. No.
I'm going to miss you.
Try not to get stuck
wherever you're going.
Arrest him! Arrest him!
God damn it!
(CAR HORNS BEEPING)
Taxi.
Thank you.
Have a good trip.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Where you go?
161 Lexington.
Please take Van Wyck
Expressway to
Queensboro Bridge.
It's faster than BQE.
Where you from?
Krakozhia. Viktor Navorski.
I'm Goran. Albania.
Oh, when do you
come to New York?
Oh! (SCOFFS)
Thursday.
Sir, you want us
to signal red,
block the south exit
and have AP
sweep every vehicle?
Sir?
5:30 from Tokyo just landed.
Got two planes on the tarmac.
Barcelona on approach.
The night is young,
and 1,500 people
are headed our way.
Everybody inside.
Come on.
Let's go.
(CAR HORNS BLARING)
Are you checking in, sir?
No, no. I don't check in.
I want to go to
this place, please.
Oh, the lobby lounge is
around the corner, sir.
They have happy hour specials
and live music every night.
Do you like jazz?
BENNY: The monitor's off.
(MEN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Uh, let's do Killer Joe.
It worked all right
last night so we'll try...
Yes?
You are Benny Golson?
Yeah. Yes, I am. Yeah.
Benny Golson,
I am Viktor Navorski.
I am from Krakozhia.
My father,
Dimitar Asenov Navorski,
was great,
great fan of your music.
Oh, a jazz fan. Fantastic.
Would you sign
your name, please?
(BAND PLAYING)
Oh-oh.
Can I do it a little later?
We have to get started now.
Just a minute.
I will wait.
Okay.
(DISTANT SIREN WAILING)
Taxi. Taxi.
Where you want to go?
I am going home.